Hugh Johnston fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Radical Campus files, 1958 - 2004; F-223-1; 2.55 m of textual records 72 sound recordings; Date range: Predominant dates of textual material in the series are 1965-1974. General note: sound recordings are located in series F-223-1-7-2.
  - Interviews, 1974 - 2003; F-223-1-7; 19 cm of textual records 72 sound recordings; General note: sound recordings are located in sub-sub-series 2.
    - Audiocassette recordings of interviews, 1974 - 2003; F-223-1-7-2; 72 sound recordings
      - Wilson, Lolita - interviewer Hugh Johnston, September 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-40 (Audio cassette OBJ-3891)
        Johnston, Hugh; Wilson, Lolita; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-223-item67.
      - Yandle, Sharon - interviewer Dino Rossi, April 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-41 (Audio cassette OBJ-3892)
        Yandle, Sharon; Rossi, Dionysios; Sound recordings
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-223-item68.
      - Stan Persky interviewed by Dino Rossi on Student radical / UBC student president, Dec 7 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-43; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4308)
        Restricted in whole due to the fragility of the medium. Consult the archivist to obtain access.
      - Mike Lebowitz interviewed by Dino Rossi, March 13 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-44; 2 audio cassettes (ca. 180 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4309, Audio cassette OBJ-4310)
      - Kenji Okuda professor of economics 1967-1987 interviewed by Dino Rossi, Jan 23 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-45; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4311)
      - Jack Blaney interviewed by John-Henry Harter, March 27 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-46; 1 audio cassette (ca 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4312)
        Pending review (no consent form). Restricted in whole due to the fragility of the medium. Consult the archivist to obtain access.
      - Marilyn Kynaston interviewed by John-Henry Harter, Aug 1 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-47; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4313)
      - Ian Andrews Director of International teacher education. Was student in 1960s, Faculty in 1970s in PDP and back in 1990s in Education, interviewed by John-Henry Harter, Mar 27 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-48; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4314)
      - Roger Blackman Associate Dean of Arts, Professor of Psychology, interviewed by Dino Rossi, Feb 20 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-49; 2 audio cassettes (ca. 180 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4315, Audio cassette OBJ-4316)
      - Len Berggren, Department of mathematics, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, December 18 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-50; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4317)
      - Roy Carlson Department of archaeology interviewed by K. Anderson, Jan 31 1986; F-223-1-7-2-0-52; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4319)
      - Alan Emmott Reeve of Burnaby at time SFU was created interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Nov 4 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-53; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4320)
      - George Pedersen President of SFU 1979-1983 interviewed by John-Henry Harter, [ca. 2001]; F-223-1-7-2-0-54; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4321)
      - Thelma Finlayson Pest Management program interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Nov 25 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-55; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4322)
      - Charles Hamilton Department of History / University Affairs in 1960s interviewed by Robin Fisher, Feb 29 1988; F-223-1-7-2-0-56; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4323)
      - John Tietz Philosophy dept, Associate Dean of Arts interviewed by Dino Rossi, Feb 1 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-57; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4324)
      - Heribert Adam PSA / SOC & ANTH interviewed by Dino Rossi, May 14 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-58; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4325)
      - Jack Diamond Board of Governors when McTaggart Cowan was president, Chancellor 1975-1978, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Nov 7 2000; F-223-1-7-2-0-59; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4326)
      - Parzival Copes Professor of economics - fisheries, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Feb 12 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-60; 3 audio cassettes (ca. 300 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4327, Audio cassette OBJ-4328, Audio cassette OBJ-4329)
      - C Rod Day Professor history dept, interviewed by Dino Rossi, Nov 28 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-61; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4330)
      - George Curtis University's Act of 1963; Naming of SFU interviewed by John-Henry Harter, Feb 9 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-62; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4331)
      - Dennis Bevington Departmental asst philosophy dept interviewed by Dino Rossi, March 8 2002; F-223-1-7-2-0-63; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4332)
      - Archie MacPherson faculty perspectives on the CAUT censure Geography prof. 1970 Dean of Faculty of Arts, Temporary Acting President, interviewed by Ken Nielsen, Mar 5 1982; F-223-1-7-2-0-64; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4333)
      - Evan Alderson, Founding director for centre for contemporary arts, Founding director of graduate liberal studies program, Dean of faculty of arts 1992-1997, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Jan 14 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-65; 2 audio cassettes (ca. 180 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4334, Audio cassette OBJ-4335)
      - Evan Alderson, Founding director for centre for contemporary arts, Founding director of graduate liberal studies program, Dean of faculty of arts 1992-1997, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Feb 11 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-66; 2 audio cassettes (ca. 180 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4336, Audio cassette OBJ-4337)
      - Evan Alderson, Founding director for centre for contemporary arts, Founding director of graduate liberal studies program, Dean of faculty of arts 1992-1997, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Jan 14, Feb 11 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-67; 3 audio cassettes (ca. 270 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4338, Audio cassette OBJ-4339, Audio cassette OBJ-4340)
      - Evan Alderson, Founding director for centre for contemporary arts, Founding director of graduate liberal studies program, Dean of faculty of arts 1992-1997, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, March 11 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-68; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4342)
      - Evan Alderson, Founding director for centre for contemporary arts, Founding director of graduate liberal studies program, Dean of faculty of arts 1992-1997, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, March 11 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-69; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4343)
      - Ralph Maud, Professor of English, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, April 10 2001; F-223-1-7-2-0-70; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4344)
      - Len Berggren, Department of Mathematics, interviewed by Hugh Johnston, Jan 23 2003; F-223-1-7-2-0-71; 1 audio cassette (ca. 60 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4345)
      - Mordecai Briemberg, Meeting of the SFU social and political forum. Speech on the history of SFU. One of the 7 faculty members who were fired, [ca. 1990]; F-223-1-7-2-0-72; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (OBJ-4346)
      - Dr. Heribert Adam, interviewed by K. Anderson, February 5, 1986; F-223-1-7-2-0-73; 1 audio cassette (ca. 90 minutes) (Audio cassette OBJ-4347)
  - Radical Campus - chapter drafts, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8; 4 cm of textual records
    Sub-series contains drafts of all the chapters of Radical Campus. Johnston's publishers, Douglas and McIntyre, reviewed the manuscript draft of Radical Campus and asked Johnston to condense the book. This sub-series includes lengthier versions of the chapters.
    - Prologue: Freedom Square and SFU's History, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 1: The Instant University, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 2: Aesthetics and Efficiency, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 3: Planning and Symbols, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 4: Berkeley North, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 5: Students Beyond the Classroom, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-6 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 6: Young, Untenured Faculty from Everywhere, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-7 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 7: Specialization and Interdiscplinary Studies, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-8 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 8: Four presidents and Four Crises, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-9 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Chapter 9: A Fifth Crisis: an Academic Strike, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-10 (Archival box - standard 223-19)
    - Epilogue: Shrum's University After 40 Years, 2003 - 2004; F-223-1-8-0-11 (Archival box - standard 223-19)